A Guide to the Tennessee Williams Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6694-e
Tennessee Williams Collection ca. 1927-1956
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6694-e
19 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1986 October 14
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Two copies of the poem " The Blanket Roll Blues, ", n.d.; TMs, 2 p.
    one signed "10 Wms" in pencil
  - The poem " A Call " by Tennessee Williams, n.d.; TMs, 1 p
    written while living in St. Louis, Missouri.
  - Poem beginning, "Come to me like a deep breath," by Tennessee Williams, 1956 Sep 10; TMs, 2 p.
    undated, with a note on the verso, dated September 10, 1956, by Edwina [Dakin Williams ?], describing this poem as "the original and only copy"
  - The poem " Elegy For An Artist (For Florence Biddle VerSteeg) " by Tennessee Williams, n.d.; TMs, 2 p.
  - Poem beginning "I dream and in my dream the ghosts appear of Chaucer, Milton, [glittering] Shakespeare," by Tennessee Williams, AMs, 2 p.
  - Poem beginning, "My eyes sometimes swim past enormous crowds," by Tennessee Williams, n.d.; TMs, 2 p.
  - The poem, " The Painted Masque, " by Tennessee Williams, n.d.; TMs, 1 p.
  - The poem, " Roses, " by Tennessee Williams, 1938 Apr; TMsS, 1 p.
    probably about his sister Rose who had recently undergone a prefrontal lobotomy as a cure for her schizophrenia
  - The poem, " The Vanished Nymph, " by Tennessee Williams, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - An elegy, "Virginia H. Jones An Appreciation," by [ Tennessee Williams], n.d.; TMs, 1 p.
    perhaps commissioned by the Daughters of the American Revolution for a deceased member
  - Fragment of a short story entitled " The Christmas Blocks, " and other incidents from Tennessee Williams early childhood, TMs, 5 p.
    possibly later incorporated into his
    Memoir
  - Fragment in which Tennessee Williams gloats over the prospects of being a passenger on a ship during the summer and describes his anger over the University [City High School ?] dropping "World History" from its curriculum, [ca. 1927?]; AMs, 1 p.
  - Fragment of a short story about a young man's discovery that he has tuberculosis, n.d.; AMs, 3 p.
  - Fragment of a short story by Tennessee Williams, 1930 Feb 21; AMsS, 1 p.
    possibly based upon his experiences on his voyage to Europe when sixteen
- Letters
  - Various stages of a letter drafted by Tennessee Williams to Wilbur Schramm at the University of Iowa, 1937 Aug 22; 7 TL, 7 p.
    [writes about entering the University of Iowa's drama department]
  - Draft of a letter from Tennessee Williams to the Registrar of the University of Iowa, [1937]; TL, 1 p.
    [writes concerning their drama department and requests a catalogue]
  - Two drafts of a letter from Tennessee Williams to judges Harold Clurman, Irwin Shaw, and Molly Day Thacker, [1939]; ALS, 2 p.
    [thanks them for the Group Theater Prize of one hundred dollars awarded to him for
    American Blues
    and mentions his employment as a featherpicker on a squab ranch near Los Angelos and his new job in a shoe store]
  - Draft of a notice to "potential producers", [ca. 1940]; TLS, 1 p.
    [decribes how Tennessee Williams' play
    Stairs to the Roof
    was based on his shoe store job], initialed by Williams
  - An incomplete farcical "letter" addressed to "Honey Chile", n.d.; TL, 1 p.
    [concerns limited letter writing]